Henry Harley Arnold Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Journals and Notebooks, circa 1908-1946 (Box 2-3, Reel 2-3)
  - 1943
    - Nov.-Dec., trip to Sextant Conference, Cairo, Egypt-Tehran, Iran See also Container 163, same heading and Container 202, same heading (Box 3, Reel 3)
  - 1944
    - June, trip to England
    - Sept., trip to Quebec Conference, Quebec, Canada
  - 1945
    - Mar.-May, trip to Europe and Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
    - June, trip to Pacific
    - July, trip to Terminal Conference, Berlin, Germany
  - 1946
    - Jan., trip to South America
- Correspondence, 1907-1967 (Box 3-38, Reel 3-38)
  - Chronological, 1907-1949 (Box 3-6, Reel 3-6)
    Correspondence and memoranda between Arnold and colleagues, friends, and the public, including incoming and outgoing letters and related material such as reports, flight records, commendations, and printed matter pertaining to Arnold's professional and personal interests.
    - 1907-1924, (10 folders) (Box 3, Reel 3)
    - 1924-1939, (10 folders) (Box 4, Reel 4)
    - 1940-1945, (9 folders) (Box 5, Reel 5)
    - 1946-1949, (2 folders) (Box 6, Reel 6)
  - Congratulatory and Condolence Letters, 1935-1950 (Box 6-10, Reel 6-10)
    Incoming and outgoing letters relating to various occasions, such as awards, promotions, and Arnold's death.
    - 1935 (Box 6, Reel 6)
      - Named assistant chief of air corps, (2 folders)
      - Promotion to brigadier general and Mackay trophy
    - 1938
      - Named chief of air corps, (3 folders); (6 folders) (Box 7, Reel 7)
    - 1940
      - Named deputy chief of staff
    - 1941
      - Promotion to major general
    - 1941-1942 (Box 8, Reel 8)
      - Promotion to lieutenant general
      - Distinguished service medal
    - 1942-1945
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - 1943
      - Promotion to four star general, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 9)
    - 1944
      - Promotion to five star general, (2 folders)
    - 1946-1950
      - Awards and special honors
    - 1949
      - Publication of Global Mission, (2 folders)
    - 1950 (Box 10, Reel 10)
      - Condolence letters, (7 folders)
  - General, 1925-1967 (Box 11-36, Reel 11-36)
    Correspondence and related material documenting Arnold's personal and professional activities and letters sent and received by his wife, Eleanor Pool Arnold.
    Arranged into an Alphabetical file, organized by name of individual or organization and topic, and a Serial file. An index for the Serial file is in box 23.
    - Alphabetical file (Box 11, Reel 11)
      - Abbott, C. G., 1942-1944
      - Adamson, Hans Christian, 1938-1945
      - Aeroclub of Washington, D.C., 1940-1944
      - Aerosphere, Ltd., 1941-1942
      - Aldrich, Winthrop W., 1942-1944
      - Aldworth, Richard T., 1943
      - American Legion, 1941-1947
      - American Red Cross, 1942-1944
      - Andrews, Frank M., 1938-1943
      - Archibald, Ann M., 1939-1943
      - Army Flyer, 1941-1944
      - Army Retiring Board, 1945-1946
      - Army-Navy Club, Washington, D.C., 1944-1946
      - Arnold, William R., 1941-1945
      - Arnold Engineering Development Center, Tullahoma, Tenn., 1967
      - Aviator's Post No. 743, 1941-1946
      - “A” miscellaneous, 1937-1953, (2 folders)
      - Backman, Gus P., 1938-1944
      - Baily, Edward P., 1938-1942
      - Bamberger, Julian M., 1939-1943
      - Barker, Frank P. K., 1939-1945
      - Barnes, Carter, 1941-1944
      - Baruch, Bernard M., 1943-1946
      - Beck, Thomas H., 1942-1945
      - Beebe, Eugene H., 1939-1946
      - Beech, Walter H., 1940-1943
      - Bell, Lawrence D., 1938-1945
      - Bellamy, Paul L., 1944
      - Benedict, M. A., 1940-1945
      - Berline, Henry A., 1940-1945
      - Blaik, Earl H., 1941-1943 (Box 12, Reel 12)
      - Block, Harry, 1942-1944
      - Boards, 1940-1944
      - Boothe, Roy, 1939-1946
      - Borglum, Lincoln and Gutzon, 1941-1942
      - Bower, Gerald E. and Melissa Hoffman, 1941
      - Boyd, Dorothea A. and William R., 1941-1945
      - Bradley, Follett, 1939-1945
      - Brant, Gerald C., 1939-1941
      - Brereton, Lewis and Lou, 1941-1942
      - Brown, Donald L., 1939
      - Bruno, Harry, 1941-1945
      - “B” miscellaneous, 1936-1946, (4 folders)
      - Campbell, L. H., Jr., 1942-1944
      - Carroll, Earl, 1942-1943
      - Carroll, Frances U., 1944
      - Carter, Amon G., 1941-1945
      - Castle, Benjamin F., 1939-1945
      - Cleveland, E. W. (“Pop”), 1943-1944
      - Clubs and lodges, 1939-1957
      - Coffyn, Frank T., 1941-1944
      - Collier trophy, 1941-1945
      - Collier's Magazine, 1941-1944
      - Collins, Ross A., 1940-1945
      - Cone, J. Carroll, 1939-1943
      - Convalescent Hospital, Pawling, N.Y., 1945 (Box 13, Reel 13)
      - Cook, A. B., 1939-1944
      - Costello, John M., 1940-1944
      - Cousins, Ralph P., 1941-1943
      - Cover, Carl A., 1940-1942
      - Cox, Albert L., 1941
      - Craig, Malin, 1939-1944
      - Curry, John F., 1939-1945
      - “C” miscellaneous, 1936-1949, undated, (4 folders)
      - Damon, Ralph S., 1943-1944
      - Dargue, Herbert A. and Marie, 1941-1942
      - Davies, Joseph I., 1940-1944
      - Davis, Michael F. and Mary, 1943
      - Davison, Frederick Trubee, 1941
      - Dill, John, Sir, 1942-1946, undated
      - Dockweiler, John F., 1936-1944, undated
      - Donations, 1945
      - Donovan, William J., 1941-1942
      - Doolittle, James H., 1939-1945, undated
      - Douglas, Donald W., 1939-1950
      - “D” miscellaneous, 1936-1946, undated, (2 folders)
      - Eaker, Ira C., and Ruth Apperson, 1935-1945
      - Eichelberger, Robert L., 1940-1942 (Box 14, Reel 14)
      - Elliott, J. E. (“Joe”), 1938-1946
      - Emmons, Harold H., 1942-1945
      - “E” miscellaneous, 1936-1950, undated, (2 folders)
      - Fairy, Richard, 1941-1946
      - Fawcett Publications, 1941
      - Fletcher, Edward, 1941-1946
      - Flying record, 1943-1946, undated
      - Football, 1938-1945
      - Ford, Corey, 1942-1945
      - Freeman, Wilfred, 1941-1942
      - Frye, Jack, 1938-1944
      - “F” miscellaneous, 1937-1950, undated, (2 folders)
      - Gardner, Lester D., 1940-1944
      - Geis, Bernard, 1942-1943
      - Giles, Barney M., 1943-1946
      - Gillespie, Eugene F., 1939-1945
      - Golding, H. Dick, 1942
      - Gorrell, Edgar S., 1941-1945 (Box 15, Reel 15)
      - Gott, Edward M., 1939-1942
      - Guthrie, William L., 1938-1945
      - “G” miscellaneous, 1937-1946, undated, (3 folders)
      - Harper & Brothers, 1941-1943
      - Harris, Arthur T., 1942
      - Harris, L. C., 1943-1944
      - Hart, Moss, 1943-1945, undated
      - Hickman, Willis, 1942-1945, undated
      - Hill, Roderick, 1941-1942
      - Hopkins, Harry L., 1942-1945, undated
      - Horner, Leonard S., 1937-1941
      - Hungerford, Viscount See Container 19, Portal, Charles F. A.
      - Hutchings, DeWitt W., 1941-1945
      - Hyatt, Frank K., 1941-1943
      - “H” miscellaneous, 1936-1948, undated, (3 folders)
      - Institute of the Aeronautical Sciences, New York, N.Y., 1940-1946 (Box 16, Reel 16)
      - “I” miscellaneous, 1938-1946, undated
      - Jenkins, J. Carden, 1941
      - Johnson, Louis, 1938-1942
      - “J” miscellaneous, 1937-1948, (2 folders)
      - Keller, R. T., 1944-1945
      - Kenney, George S., 1941-1945
      - Kilmer, Mary E., 1941-1944, undated
      - Kindelberger, James H., 1939-1945
      - King, Ernest J., 1942-1944
      - Kreusser, O. T., 1940-1942
      - “K” miscellaneous, 1939-1958, undated, (2 folders)
      - Lahm, Frank P., 1941-1942
      - Landis, Reed G., 1937-1945
      - Landon School for Boys, Bethesda, Md., 1940-1945
      - Lanphier, Thomas S., 1943-1944
      - Life Magazine, 1941-1944
      - Lincoln, Rush B., 1941-1942
      - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1938-1942, (4 folders)
      - Lodwick, Albert I., 1939-1945 (Box 17, Reel 17)
      - Lovett, Robert A., 1941-1945, undated
      - Lower Merion School District, Ardmore, Pa., 1939-1950
      - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1945
      - “L” miscellaneous, 1938-1946, undated, (2 folders)
      - Mark Twain Society, Webster Groves, Mo., 1942
      - Marshall, George C., 1943-1944, undated
      - Martin, Frederick L., 1940-1944
      - Martin, Glenn L., 1940-1945
      - Marx, Louis, 1939-1946, (2 folders)
      - McGee, James M., 1937-1944
      - McStay, Carl E., 1936-1945
      - Meigs, Merrill C., 1941-1945
      - Military Order of Foreign Wars of the United States, Pennsylvania Commandery, Philadelphia, Pa., 1939-1944
      - Military Order of the World War, Washington, D.C., 1942-1944
      - Milner, Nate, 1941-1944
      - Morgan, William V., 1944
      - Moseley, C. C., 1940-1944
      - Mosier, O. M., 1940-1944
      - “M” miscellaneous, 1936-1950, undated, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 18, Reel 18)
      - Nash Motor Co., Kenosha, Wis., 1940-1941
      - National Aeronautical Society, Washington, D.C., 1939-1941
      - National Geographic Society, Washington, D.C., 1938-1946
      - National Safety Council, Chicago, Ill., 1941-1944
      - Northrop, John K., 1940-1945
      - “N-O” miscellaneous, 1938-1951, (3 folders)
      - Parks, Floyd L., 1939-1944
      - Parson, John E., 1941-1942
      - Patton, George S., 1943-1946
      - Pedersen, Edwin, 1939-1946, (2 folders) (Box 19, Reel 19)
      - Portal, Charles F. A., 1941-1945
      - “P” miscellaneous, 1936-1946, undated, (2 folders)
      - Reilly, Henry, 1942-1943
      - Rickenbacker, Eddie, 1942-1946, (2 folders)
      - Riddle, John Paul, 1942-1945
      - Robins, Dorothy, 1939-1945, undated
      - “R” miscellaneous, 1937-1950, undated, (2 folders)
      - Shelmire, Horace W., 1943-1945
      - Society of American Military Engineers, Washington, D.C., 1941
      - Society of Automotive Engineers, New York, N.Y., 1939-1940
      - Somervell, Brehon, 1944 (Box 20, Reel 20)
      - Spaatz, Carl, 1941-1948, undated
      - Stark, Harold R. (“Betty”), 1941-1944
      - Statements before Congress, 1949
      - Stettinius, Edward R., 1941-1945
      - Stover, Mabel Robinson, 1941-1945
      - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1942-1945
      - “S” miscellaneous, 1925-1950, undated, (4 folders)
      - Thomas, Lowell, 1942-1945
      - “T” miscellaneous, 1939-1952, undated, (2 folders)
      - United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., 1934-1951, (4 folders) (Box 21, Reel 21)
      - “U” miscellaneous, 1941, 1947
      - Vaughan, Guy, 1936-1946
      - Veterans of Foreign Wars, Kansas City, Mo., 1942-1966
      - “V” miscellaneous, 1936-1945, undated
      - Wallace, Walter J., 1939-1940
      - Walsh, James L., 1941-1942
      - Warner, Harry M., 1941-1945
      - Warner, Jack L., 1941-1946
      - Weaver, Walter R., 1939-1945
      - Weikert, John M., 1941-1943
      - Wilby, F. B., 1940-1945
      - Wilson, Gill Robb, 1942-1945
      - Winged Victory, play by Moss Hart, 1943-1945, (3 folders)
      - Winged Warfare, 1940-1944 (Box 22, Reel 22)
      - Wings Club, New York, N.Y., 1942-1946
      - Wittschen, Emma, 1940-1946
      - Wood, Robert E., 1940-1946
      - Wright, Burdette S., 1939-1945, undated
      - “W” miscellaneous, 1938-1948, undated, (2 folders)
      - Yorktown Memorial, Yorktown, Va., 1936-1937
      - Yount, Barton K., 1941-1946
      - “Y-Z” miscellaneous, 1936-1946, (2 folders)
    - Serial file, 1946-1950 (Box 23, Reel 23)
      - Index
      - Nos. 1-33 (Ad-Au), (4 folders)
      - Nos. 33-70 (Au-Bo), (6 folders) (Box 24, Reel 24)
      - Nos. 70 1/2-159 (Bo-Du), (6 folders) (Box 25, Reel 25)
      - Nos. 160-264 (Ea-Ha), (5 folders) (Box 26, Reel 26)
      - Nos. 265-385 (He-Ly), (6 folders) (Box 27, Reel 27)
      - Nos. 386-438 (Ma-Mo), (5 folders) (Box 28, Reel 28)
      - Nos. 439-523 (Mo-Pi), (6 folders) (Box 29, Reel 29)
      - Nos. 524-581 (Pl-Si), (5 folders) (Box 30, Reel 30)
      - Nos. 582-651 (Sk-Va), (5 folders) (Box 31, Reel 31)
      - Nos. 652-700 (Va-Zi), (5 folders) (Box 32, Reel 32)
      - No. 707 (biographical material) (Box 33, Reel 33)
      - No. 708 (birthday congratulations)
      - No. 709 (business offers index)
      - No. 710 (change of title)
      - No. 711 (Christmas)
      - No. 712 (direct personal interest)
      - No. 713 (honorary degrees)
      - No. 714 (California Fish and Game Commission), (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 34, Reel 34)
      - No. 715 (journalism index)
      - No. 718 (memberships) (Box 35, Reel 35)
      - No. 719 (museums), (3 folders)
      - No. 720 (portraits)
      - No. 721 (property) (Box 36, Reel 36)
      - No. 724 (trips)
  - Personal, 1930-1950 (Box 36-38, Reel 36-38)
    Letters between Arnold and friends, colleagues, and the public pertaining to personal and professional interests.
    - Jan. 1930-June 1932, (5 folders) (Box 36, Reel 36)
    - July 1932-Sept. 1933, (5 folders) (Box 37, Reel 37)
    - Oct. 1933-Feb. 1950, (5 folders) (Box 38, Reel 38)
- Military File, 1913-1951 (Box 39-226, Reel 39-227)
  - Decimal File, 1940-1945 (Box 39-152, Reel 39-152)
    Correspondence, memoranda, reports, orders, directives, clippings, and printed matter documenting Arnold's military career.
    Arranged by the Dewey number system adopted by the army in 1918. Containers 39-60 include a name and subject index to this subseries and are shelved with oversize material.
    - Name index (Box OV 39, Reel 39)
      - A-B
      - C-E (Box OV 40, Reel 40)
      - F-Hl (Box OV 41, Reel 41)
      - Ho-L (Box OV 42, Reel 42)
      - M-O (Box OV 43, Reel 43)
      - P-Se (Box OV 44, Reel 44)
      - Sh-T (Box OV 45, Reel 45)
      - U-Z (Box OV 46, Reel 46)
    - Subject index (Box OV 47, Reel 47)
      - Ab-Ai
      - Ai-Ba (Box OV 48, Reel 48)
      - Be-Ce (Box OV 49, Reel 49)
      - Ch-Co (Box OV 50, Reel 50)
      - Cr-Ep (Box OV 51, Reel 51)
      - Eq-F (Box OV 52, Reel 52)
      - G-Im (Box OV 53, Reel 53)
      - In-L (Box OV 54, Reel 54)
      - M-N (Box OV 55, Reel 55)
      - O-Po (Box OV 56, Reel 56)
      - Pr-Re (Box OV 57, Reel 57)
      - Re-Sq (Box OV 58, Reel 58)
      - St-To (Box OV 59, Reel 59)
      - Tr-Z (Box OV 60, Reel 60)
    - Nos. 000.1-000.92, (6 folders) (Box 61, Reel 61)
    - No. 000.93
      - 1-59, (2 folders)
      - 60-139, (2 folders) (Box 62, Reel 62)
    - Nos. 001-008, (8 folders)
    - Nos. 011-045.92, (7 folders) (Box 63, Reel 63)
    - No. 047.2
      - 1-60
      - 61-212, (2 folders) (Box 64, Reel 64)
    - Nos. 050-080, (5 folders)
    - Nos. 091-160, (11 folders) (Box 65, Reel 65)
    - Nos. 200.2-210.105, (9 folders) (Box 66, Reel 66)
    - No. 210.2
      - 1-300, (2 folders)
      - 301-560, (2 folders) (Box 67, Reel 67)
    - Nos. 210.26-210.3
    - No. 210.31
      - 1-450, (3 folders)
      - 451-780, (5 folders) (Box 68, Reel 68)
      - By country
    - Nos. 210.311-210.32, (2 folders)
    - Nos. 210.33-210.5, (6 folders) (Box 69, Reel 69)
    - Nos. 210.63-210.673 (Box 70, Reel 70)
    - No. 210.68
      - Africa-Egypt, (4 folders)
      - England
        - 1-260, (2 folders)
        - 261-475, (2 folders) (Box 71, Reel 71)
      - Europe-Twentieth Air Force
        - 1-50, (2 folders)
        - 51-578, (6 folders) (Box 72, Reel 72)
    - Nos. 210.681-210.72, (2 folders)
    - Nos. 210.8-220.3, (5 folders) (Box 73, Reel 73)
    - Nos. 220.31-241.19, (8 folders) (Box 74, Reel 74)
    - Nos. 241.3-311.1, (7 folders) (Box 75, Reel 75)
    - Nos. 311.13-311.54, (5 folders) (Box 76, Reel 76)
    - Nos. 312.1-312.4, (3 folders) (Box 77, Reel 77)
    - No. 313.3
      - 1-55, (3 folders)
      - 56-189, (7 folders) (Box 78, Reel 78)
    - Nos. 313.5-313.7
    - Nos. 314.7-314.81, (2 folders) (Box 79, Reel 79)
    - No. 319.1
      - 1-32, (3 folders)
      - 33-243, (6 folders) (Box 80, Reel 80)
      - 244-501, (5 folders) (Box 81, Reel 81)
      - Air Technical Service Command-Intelligence, (2 folders)
      - Office of Strategic Services-Twentieth Air Force (Box 82, Reel 82)
    - No. 320.2
      - 1-200, (5 folders)
      - 201-555, (6 folders) (Box 83, Reel 83)
      - 556-1138, (7 folders) (Box 84, Reel 84)
      - 1139-1957, (6 folders) (Box 85, Reel 85)
      - Africa-Airborne Army, (3 folders) (Box 86, Reel 86)
      - Aircraft Warning Service
        - 1-109, (2 folders)
        - 110-151 (Box 87, Reel 87)
      - Alaska-Canada, (5 folders)
      - Caribbean Defense Command-Eastern theater, (6 folders) (Box 88, Reel 88)
      - Eighth Air Force, (5 folders) (Box 89, Reel 89)
      - England-Iceland, (6 folders) (Box 90, Reel 90)
      - India-Technical training command, (8 folders) (Box 91, Reel 91)
      - Tenth Air Force-“X”, (6 folders) (Box 92, Reel 92)
    - Nos. 320.3-321.19
    - No. 322
      - 1-128
      - European theater operations-postwar (Box 93, Reel 93)
    - Nos. 322.011-331.4, (3 folders)
    - No. 333
      - 1-144, (2 folders)
      - 145-244 (Box 94, Reel 94)
      - Caribbean Air Force-Scientific Advisory Group
    - Nos. 333.1-333.5
    - No. 333.9
      - 1-115, (2 folders)
      - 116-449, (6 folders) (Box 95, Reel 95)
      - 451-637, (4 folders) (Box 96, Reel 96)
      - Alaska-Mead Committee
    - No. 334
      - 1-200, (2 folders)
      - Aid Society-United States, Canadian Inter-Service Flying Control Committee, (3 folders) (Box 97, Reel 97)
    - Nos. 334.3-336.4, (3 folders)
    - Nos. 336.6-350.1, (7 folders) (Box 98, Reel 98)
    - No. 350.2
      - 1-35
      - Canada-Yugoslavia, (2 folders) (Box 99, Reel 99)
    - Nos. 350.6-352.17, (3 folders)
    - No. 353
      - 1-78
      - 79-456, (7 folders) (Box 100, Reel 100)
      - Air ground cooperation-Universal military training (Box 101, Reel 100)
    - Nos. 353.1-360.1, (5 folders)
    - No. 360.02
      - 1-89
      - Brazil-North Africa, (3 folders) (Box 102, Reel 100)
    - Nos. 360.11-360.112
    - No. 360.33
      - 1-171, (3 folders)
      - 172-288 (Box 103, Reel 100)
    - Nos. 360.4-370.01, (5 folders)
    - Nos. 370.05-370.091 (Box 104, Reel 104)
    - No. 370.2
      - 1-192, (6 folders)
      - 193-284 (Box 105, Reel 105)
      - Air force combat control-Eighth Air Force, (4 folders)
      - England-Italy, (6 folders) (Box 106, Reel 106)
      - Japan-Twentieth Air Force, (3 folders) (Box 107, Reel 107)
    - Nos. 370.24-370.32, (5 folders)
    - No. 370.5 (Box 108, Reel 108)
      - 1-689, (5 folders)
      - Africa-“X”, (3 folders) (Box 109, Reel 109)
    - Nos. 370.7-371
    - No. 373
      - 1-99, (2 folders)
      - 100-284, (4 folders) (Box 110, Reel 110)
      - Newfoundland
    - Nos. 373.01-380.3, (3 folders)
    - No. 381
      - 1-124
      - Africa-MacDill Field, Tampa, Fla., (8 folders) (Box 111, Reel 111)
      - Mexico-War plans, (6 folders) (Box 112, Reel 112)
    - Nos. 381.4-384.6, (6 folders) (Box 113, Reel 113)
    - No. 385
      - 1-93, (2 folders)
      - 94-254, (2 folders) (Box 114, Reel 114)
      - Japan
    - Nos. 385.2-387
    - No. 400
      - 1-372, (5 folders)
      - Africa-“X”, (5 folders) (Box 115, Reel 115)
    - Nos. 400.111-400.303, (2 folders)
    - Nos. 400.312-413.2, (3 folders) (Box 116, Reel 116)
    - No. 413.44
      - 1-190, (3 folders)
      - 191-647, (5 folders) (Box 117, Reel 117)
      - Ascension Island-West Africa
    - Nos. 413.45-413.6
    - Nos. 413.62-430.3, (5 folders) (Box 118, Reel 118)
    - Nos. 431-452.09, (4 folders) (Box 119, Reel 119)
    - No. 452.1
      - 2-100, (2 folders)
      - 101-429, (8 folders) (Box 120, Reel 120)
      - 431-830, (6 folders) (Box 121, Reel 121)
      - 831-1540, (7 folders) (Box 122, Reel 122)
      - 1541-1715, (2 folders) (Box 123, Reel 123)
      - Africa-Chile, (7 folders)
      - China-Ecuador, (2 folders) (Box 124, Reel 124)
      - England
        - 1-201, (6 folders)
        - 202-439, (3 folders) (Box 125, Reel 125)
      - European theater of operations-Hawaii, (3 folders)
      - Iceland-Postwar air force, (7 folders) (Box 126, Reel 126)
      - Russia-Switzerland, (7 folders) (Box 127, Reel 127)
      - Torch-Yugoslavia, (5 folders) (Box 128, Reel 128)
    - No. 452.11
      - 1-98, (2 folders)
      - 99-271 (Box 129, Reel 129)
      - Iceland-Superchargers
    - Nos. 452.12-452.33, (2 folders)
    - No. 452.4
      - Autogiros-Gliders, (3 folders)
    - Nos. 452.9-458.11, (2 folders) (Box 130, Reel 130)
    - No. 461
      - 1-186, (4 folders)
      - 187-302 (Box 131, Reel 131)
      - Newsletter, (5 folders)
    - Nos. 462-463
    - Nos. 463.7-470, (7 folders) (Box 132, Reel 132)
    - Nos. 470.1-471.52, (6 folders) (Box 133, Reel 133)
    - No. 471.6
      - 1-75, (2 folders)
      - 76-503, (6 folders) (Box 134, Reel 134)
      - Aerial mines-Smoke screens and bombs
    - Nos. 471.82-471.94
    - Nos. 472-475.73, (5 folders) (Box 135, Reel 135)
    - No. 475.731
      - 1-7, (2 folders)
      - 8-21, (4 folders) (Box 136, Reel 136)
    - Nos. 475.9-545.4, (5 folders)
    - Nos. 560-574, (3 folders) (Box 137, Reel 137)
    - No. 580
      - 1-146, (3 folders)
      - Air transport command
        - 1-53
        - 54-438, (6 folders) (Box 138, Reel 138)
      - Aviation objectives, (4 folders) (Box 139, Reel 139)
      - Greenland-South Pacific, (5 folders) (Box 140, Reel 140)
    - Nos. 580.2-600.05, (2 folders)
    - Nos. 600.1-600.96, (6 folders) (Box 141, Reel 141)
    - Nos. 601-638, (4 folders) (Box 142, Reel 142)
    - No. 660.2
      - 1-17
      - Aircraft warning service
        - 1-98, (2 folders)
        - 101-191, (2 folders) (Box 143, Reel 143)
      - Mexico-Sault Ste. Marie, Mich.
    - Nos. 660.3-676.1, (3 folders)
    - No. 676.3
      - 2-103
      - Alaska-Greenland
      - Hawaii-Russia (Box 144, Reel 144)
    - Nos. 676.4-684
    - No. 686
      - 1-92, (3 folders)
      - 94-200, (6 folders) (Box 145, Reel 145)
      - 201-618, (3 folders) (Box 146, Reel 146)
      - Africa
      - Alaska
        - 1-49, (2 folders)
        - 51-118, (3 folders) (Box 147, Reel 147)
      - Arabia-Eglin Field, Fla., (3 folders)
      - England-Hawaii, (6 folders) (Box 148, Reel 148)
      - Hawaii to Philippines air route-Nicaragua, (6 folders) (Box 149, Reel 149)
      - North Atlantic ferry route-Wake Island, (4 folders) (Box 150, Reel 150)
    - Nos. 700-702.5
    - No. 704
      - 4
      - 6, (4 folders) (Box 151, Reel 151)
      - 9-51 (Box 152, Reel 152)
    - Nos. 705-825.1, (2 folders)
  - Message File, 1941-1946 (Box 153-164, Reel 153-164)
    Chiefly incoming and outgoing cables and related material, such as reports, logs, and lists pertaining to military matters.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of individual or agency, type of material, or topic.
    - Alaska, Aug.-Sept. 1942 (Box 153, Reel 153)
    - Arnold, incoming and outgoing
      - Oct. 1942-Aug. 1943, (8 folders)
      - Sept. 1943-Mar. 1945, (12 folders) (Box 154, Reel 154)
      - Apr.-Dec. 1945, (8 folders) (Box 155, Reel 155)
    - Cable instructions and personnel, Oct. 1941-Dec. 1943 (Box 156, Reel 156)
    - Cable lists, Dec. 1941-Aug. 1945
    - Cairo, Egypt, Aug. 1942-Feb. 1943
    - Chungking, (now known as Chongqing), China, Jan.-Feb. 1943
    - Drafts, Sept. 1942-Apr. 1943
    - Eaker, Ira C.
      - London, England, May 1943
      - Manila, Tokyo, and Alaska, Apr.-May 1946
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., London, England
      - 8 Feb.-12 Oct. 1942, (2 folders)
      - 13-31 Oct. 1942, (2 folders) (Box 157, Reel 157)
    - Freedom Algiers, Dec. 1942-Feb. 1943, (2 folders)
    - Harmon, Millard F., South Pacific, Oct. 1942-Jan. 1943
    - London, England
      - From Arnold, Apr. 1941-Sept. 1943
      - From Spaatz, Carl, Sept.-Nov. 1942
      - United States forces and commanding general, European theater
        - Aug.-Sept. 1942
        - Oct. 1942-Feb. 1943, (2 folders) (Box 158, Reel 158)
    - London, England, and North Africa, Jan.-Sept. 1943
    - MacArthur, Douglas, Feb. 1942-Feb. 1943
    - Miscellaneous incoming
      - Mar. 1942-Oct. 1943, (4 folders)
      - Nov. 1943-Mar. 1944, (6 folders) (Box 159, Reel 159)
      - Apr.-June 1944, (6 folders) (Box 160, Reel 160)